<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<product>
  <title>Colony Collapse Disorder</title>
  <release-dates>
    <release-date>9/19/2016</release-date>
  </release-dates>
  <website>https://freebrunch.itch.io/colony-collapse-disorder</website>

  <platforms>
    <platform>
      <name>Itch.io (Playable in Browser)</name>
      <link>https://freebrunch.itch.io/colony-collapse-disorder</link>
    </platform>
  </platforms>

  <prices>
    <price>
      <currency></currency>
      <value>Free</value>
    </price>
  </prices>
 
  <description>Colony Collapse Disorder (CCD) is a procedurally generated adventure game where you play as an Oakland bee scouring a flower field. You must maintain honey reserves, navigate randomized encounters, and most importantly produce Queen Bees.</description>

  <histories>
    <history>
      <header>How it Started</header>
      <text>The first programming I ever learned was through an online web development certification. I learned html, css. and some javascript for making simple web pages. And even though these aren't traditional game development tools, I was sure gonna try and make a game with them!</text>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Point and Click</header>
      <text>One of the tutorials I was doing for my web development classes was a javascript framwork called "Knockout.js". And Knockout.js had a core feature called "Automatic UI Refresh - When your data model's state changes, your UI updates automatically". Sounds like a game engine right?? I realized I could assign data to css elements on a page and manipulate all the elements on the page based on click information.</text>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>BEES</header>
      <text>I now had a dynamic single page canvas on which to create my game from. I was obsessed with becoming a beekeeper at the time so I thought it would be cool to go on an adventure as a bee in my game. I combined elements from point-and-click adventure games and roguelike games and my imagination ran wild. I created a hexagonal "flower field" grid for the player to click through. And I drew comical random events to stumble upon. I even hooked up a live weather API for Oakland, CA (where I was living at the time) for that sweet sweet "immersion". CCD was born. I shared with my friends and family and was giddy that I had actually made a playable game. Still so proud of it to this day.</text>
    </history>
  </histories>

  <features>
    <feature>Playable in browser</feature>
    <feature>Global high score leaderboard</feature>
    <feature>Live weather</feature>
    <feature>Artful, high fidelity visuals to immerse you in the adventure</feature>
    <feature>Visit local flowers every step of the way</feature>
  </features>

  <!-- You can set your widgets here (optional): -->
  <widgets>
    <itch>
      475686
    </itch>
  </widgets>

  <press-can-request-copy>true</press-can-request-copy>
  <monetization-permission>monetize</monetization-permission>

  <!-- <awards>
    <award>
      <description></description>
      <info></info>
    </award>
  </awards> -->

  <additionals>
    <additional>
      <title>Game Development Blog</title>
      <link>http://bthomas2622.github.io/gamedevblog/index.html</link>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Game Monetization</title>
      <description>Ben Thomas allows for the contents of Colony Collapse Disorder to be published through video broadcasting services for any commercial or non-commercial purposes. Monetization of videos created containing assets from Colony Collapse Disorder is legally and explicitly allowed by Ben Thomas</description>
      <link></link>
    </additional>
  </additionals>

  <credits>
    <credit>
      <person>Ben Thomas</person>
      <role>Design, Programming, Art</role>
      <website>http://bthomas2622.github.io/</website>
    </credit>
  </credits>

  <contacts>
    <contact>
      <name>Ben Thomas</name>
      <mail>benthomasdeveloper@gmail.com</mail>
    </contact>
  </contacts>
</product>
