<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<company>
  <title>Ben Thomas</title>
  <based-in>Berkeley, CA</based-in>
  <founding-date>02/12/1992 (birthday)</founding-date>
  <website>http://bthomas2622.github.io/</website>
  <press-contact>
    benthomasdeveloper@gmail.com
  </press-contact>

  <analytics></analytics>

  <socials>
    <social>
      <name>Twitter @freebrunch</name>
      <link>
        https://twitter.com/freebrunch
      </link>
    </social>
    <social>
      <name>Youtube</name>
      <link>
        https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLmiIR_rnAzUoC01y2C_JqA
      </link>
    </social>
  </socials>

  <description>Ben Thomas is an independent game developer building distinct strategic games that bring people together.</description>

  <!-- Choose between a single block: -->
  <!-- <history></history> -->

  <!-- Or multiple blocks: -->
  <histories>
    <history>
      <header>Bio</header>
      <text>I was born in Ridgewood, NJ and grew up in Atlanta, GA. I have fond memories going to the pool during the hot summer days then staying up all night playing N64 and later Halo 2. I wasn't sure what I wanted to do with my life, but I knew I liked math so I studied mechanical engineering at Georgia Tech. I now reside in the Bay Area and outside my day job I like dreaming up fun game projects to learn skills for and work on. I love hanging out with friends, hiking, non-fiction books, and NBA twitter. I am passionate about urban planning, social justice, and oatmeal.</text>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Colony Collapse Disorder + Space Canoe (2016)</header>
      <text>The first games I ever made. Colony Collapse Disorder (CCD) is a procedurally generated adventure game where you play as an Oakland bee scouring a flower field. You must maintain honey reserves, navigate randomized encounters, and most importantly produce Queen Bees. Space Canoe is an arcade game where you paddle through space and dodge asteroids.</text>
    </history>
    <history>
      <header>Nectar of the Gods (2020)</header>
      <text>My first commercial game. It was difficult to start making. It took me years to kinda work through the imposter syndrome and anxiety that comes with it. But I got through it! I was inspired by the “rock paper scissors” tactics and mental reflexes of fast paced strategy games like starcraft and speed chess. I started making Nectar of the Gods on nights and weekends while working as a software engineer in 2019. I commited to full time development in mid 2020. What resulted was an unquenchable multiplayer real-time strategy game where bugs clash over the sweet nectar of sugary beverages.</text>
    </history>
  </histories>

  <!-- <trailers>
    <trailer>
      <name></name> -->

      <!-- Pick one: -->
      <!-- <youtube> -->
        <!-- Video ID only, not the full URL -->
      <!-- </youtube>
    </trailer>
  </trailers> -->

  <!-- <awards>
    <award>
      <description></description>
      <info></info>
    </award>
  </awards> -->

  <!-- <quotes>
    <quote>
      <description></description>
      <name></name>
      <website></website>
      <link></link>
    </quote>
  </quotes> -->

  <additionals>
    <additional>
      <title>Ben Thomas Game Dev Blog</title>
      <link>http://bthomas2622.github.io/gamedevblog/index.html</link>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Itch.io Home</title>
      <link>https://freebrunch.itch.io/</link>
    </additional>
    <additional>
      <title>Ben Thomas Personal Website</title>
      <link>http://bthomas2622.github.io/</link>
    </additional>
  </additionals>

  <credits>
    <credit>
      <person>Ben Thomas</person>
      <role>Designer, Programmer, Artist, Sound</role>
    </credit>
    <credit>
      <person>Tiffany Peng Hwa</person>
      <role>Collaborator, Musician</role>
    </credit>
  </credits>

  <contacts>
    <contact>
      <name>Email</name>
      <mail>benthomasdeveloper@gmail.com</mail>
    </contact>
    <contact>
      <name>Twitter</name>
      <link>
        https://twitter.com/freebrunch
      </link>
    </contact>
  </contacts>

</company>
